Hello.
The next thing we're going to do is set up some jumping and falling animations for our player character.
If we head over to the Warrior animation source, I want us to create a new animation sequence.
And if you just click F2 with the animation selected, I will allow you to quickly rename it.
I'm just going to call this one jumping.
And on the animation data, just like the jumping animation and create a new animation sequence and
call this one pulling.
And on the animation data, select the falling flipbook intro.
Save this and head over to our Warrior Animation blueprint.
We can just break the link here somewhere.
Right click and go break link.
And I'm just going to right click and look for new state machine.
And I got from here to here.
So inside this new state machine, I'm going to handle all the animations for my player character.
I just wanted to showcase this earlier.
We can copy this as we're going to head inside here.
And out.
We just want to go up here and look for Animation State just like this and call this the idle slash
run.
State, we can double click and head inside here and just paste what we copied.
And just hook this up here.
So the reason we're having this inside here is it just makes it, it cleaner and it'll make it a bit
easier when we add stuff like jumping and other animations later on.
So I'm just going to go back to my atom graph and delete this.
We can head back to our new state machine.
So we set up all happen when our character is either standing still or running.
Now I'm going to set up what happens when my character is jumping, start falling.
So initially our character is going to be in the run state in order to enter the German state.
We can just drag off here for Animation State and just pull the state jump.
Head inside here and just right click and for the play jumping animation.
So this little idle run Toronto jumping represents what's going to need to happen in order for our character
to enter this dynamic animation state.
Just double click and head inside here.
So in order for our characters to enter the jumping state, we can drag in our player reference and
just drag up here and look for is falling.
And hook us up.
So if our character is appalling, then they're going to enter the jumping stage.
From our jumping state, our player character is going to then enter their fooling state to just drag
a player and for animation states and call this full.
So click inside here and just right click for play.
Work.
So in order for our character to enter the fooling state, we can drag in our player BP, and we want
to get their velocity.
All this time.
We want to break back to free apps and won't be checking their velocity in the Z axis.
So if our characters velocity in the Z axis is ever less than.
Zero.
That basically means our character is falling down.
If our character is ever falling down, then we want them to be doing that falling animation.
So from here into here.
Then to get from our folding back to our idle slash run track snood and hook up here.
If all play a character is ever in the working state, then we'll make it.
So they go back to their walking slash idle animation so we can just drag off for is walking.
And from here into here.
And now I could compile those this and go play.
If I jump out to be in the jumping and then go to that fooling state when they're fooling.
So I'm just going to increase my characters jump so a bit more clear.
Some good here for Trump.
And make something like 1200.
And add some debug so you can see the character's velocity in the z axis.
So I'm just going to right click and print.
Spring and hike up see into here.
So you can see our velocity in the Z axis.
And hit this up here and just go compile.
So we're going to play.
Currently my z axis is here.
If I initially jump.
Then becomes a positive value.
As I fall down, it becomes a negative value.
So when my character is velocity in the z axis becomes a negative value.
We enter the falling animation stage.
Who's going to remove that?
That's hopefully you should now understand that.
And with that, we have set up some jumping animations for our player character.